Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Individual songs in English by title, 1.
  - Frenchy, Come to Yankee Land
    By Sam Ehrlich and Con Conrad. New York: Broadway Music Corporation, c. 1919. A follow-up to Oh! Frenchy (see below).
  - The Friendly Doctor
    By Irving Caesar, simplified piano arrangements by Sydney Green. New York: Irving Caesar, c. 1948. A health song for children, one of many written by Caesar. Sung by the "doctor."
  - Funny Bones: Rag
    Composed by C. L. Woolsey. Detroit and New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c.1909.
  - Germs, Germs, Germs
    Words and music by Theodore Friebus. Boston: Ernest S. Williams, c. 1910. From the "Musical Extravaganza '1915'." Comic song sung by the "doctor."
  - Get Well Soon
    Words by Tom Harrison, music by Donald Phillips. London: Lawrence Wright Music Co., Ltd., c. 1954. Recorded by Dickie Valentine on Decca Records.
  - The Girl Who Wears a Red Cross on Her Sleeve
    Cover and first page of music only. Words and music by William Mahoney. New York: P. J. Howley Music Co., c. 1915. On Red Cross nurses in World War I.
  - Girls of France
    Words and music by Alfred Bryan, Edgar Leslie, and Harry Ruby. New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder, c. 1918. On nurses in France in World War I.
  - Glory of Womanhood Waltz
    Composed by Harry J. Lincoln. Williamsport, Pa.: Vandersloot Music Publishing Co., c. 1917. Image of a World War I nurse on the cover.
  - Go Call the Doctor & Be Quick! Or Anti Calomel
    By J. J. Hutchinson. New York: William Hall & Son, c. 1843. "Sung at the Concerts of the Hutchinson Family." Dedicated to Dr. W. Beach [a founder of eclectic school of medicine]. See also "The Keys of Love, and Calomel Song."
  - Good-night, Nurse: Comic Song
    Words by Thomas Gray, music by W. Raymond Walker. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1912. Illustration of a nurse at the door.
  - Good-night, Nurse: Comic Song
    Words by Thomas Gray, music by W. Raymond Walker. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1912. Photograph of Ray Samuels on the cover.
  - Good-night, Nurse: Comic Song
    Words by Thomas Gray, music by W. Raymond Walker. New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c. 1912. Photograph of Mae West on the cover.
  - Good-Night Nursie
    Words and music by Scott Saunders. London: B. Feldman & Co., c. 1920. Sung by Florrie Forde.
  - The Gouty Old Bachelor
    "Composed and arranged by Joseph Hart." London: Mayhew & Co., n.d. (early 19th cent.). Sung by Mr. Hart.
  - The Greatest Little Mother in the World
    "By Willie Weston[,] Kendis, Brockman & Nat Vincent." New York: Kendis-Brockman Music Co., c. 1918. On nurses in World War I.
  - Harriet Island March (Box 3)
    Composed by Franz Stollwerk. St. Paul, Minn.: Franz Stollwerk, c. 1908. Dedicated to Dr. Justus Ohage. Dr. Ohage was Commissioner of Health for the city of St. Paul, 1899-1907, and founder of the public baths on Harriet Island.
  - The Harvey Memorial: Grand March
    Composed by H. S. Roberts. London: J. McDowell & Co., n.d. (ca. 1878). "Composed in Honor of the Tercentenary of the Birth of that Illustrious Physician Dr. [William] Harvey, Born at Folkestone, 1578."
  - A Headache Tomorrow (Or a Heartache Tonight)
    Words and music by Chick Rains. Nashville: Blue Lake Music/Chick Rains Music, c. 1980.
  - Heart Attack
    Words and music by Steve Kipner and Paul Bliss. New York: April Music, c. 1982. Recorded by Olivia Newton-John on MCA Records.
  - Here's to the P. S. C. [Palmer School of Chiropractic]
    Words by Harry E. Vedder, music by Melvia N. Burich. Davenport, Iowa: Melvia N. Burich, c. 1919.
  - He's in the Infirmary Now
    Words and Music by J. P. Long. London: The Lawrence Wright Music Co., c. 1933. "Comedy Song, Fox-trot."
  - Hey Doc!
    Words by Kim Gannon, music by Edgar Sampson. New York: Advanced Music Corporation, c. 1941.
  - High Fever
    Words by Charlie Harrison, music by Joe Sanders. Chicago: Ted Browne Music Co., c. 1926. "High Fever Blues."
  - His Remedies
    Words by Harry Dillon, music by John Dillon. New York: M. Witmark & Sons., 1892. Contains a long list of ineffective remedies.
  - Hospital Blues
    Words and music by Clayton A. Sanders. Indianapolis: Clayton A. Sanders, c. 1954. Recorded by Sanders Sisters and Colored Chorus. Cover image is of a black man in pajamas sitting on a hospital bed.
  - How Would You Put a Poultice on a Fly?
    Words and music by J. Howie-Milligan. Copyright by Cecil Lennox, Ltd., 1938. 1938. Exclusively published by Mills Music, New York." "Comedy Song Fox-Trot." From Mills Standard Song Library.
  - The Human System, or, The Family Physiologist
    Words and music by George Arthurs. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1910. "Humorous patter song" sung by the doctor. Sung by Will Bentley.
  - Hush A Bye Baby! Didn't He Yell! (For Mammy and Bottle and Ridge's as Well)
    Words and music by Charles Townley, arranged by W. Williams. London: Francis Bros. & Day, n.d. (late 19th cent.). Sung by Sidney Franks and also by James Francis of the Mohawk Minstrels. The song refers to and depicts a proprietary medicine, Dr. Ridge's Food for Infants, but was published by a major publishing house, rather than by the patent remedy company.
  - The Hydro: Humorous Musical Sketch
    Words and music by Edward Kent. London: Reeder & Walsh, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.)..
  - I Ain't Got Weary Yet
    Words by Howard Johnson, music by Percy Weinrich. New York: Leo Feist, c. 1918. World War I song with a brief reference to war wounds and nurses.
  - I Am So Cold
    Cover only. Words and music by John Cooke, Jr. London: Francis Bros. & Day, n.d. (19th cent.?) Cover illustration shows a man bathing his feet in a steamy tub, as well as various remedies.
  - I Don't Need No Doctor
    Words and music by Nicholas Ashford, Valerie Simpson, and Josie Armstead. Hollywood, California: Baby Monica Music, Inc., and New York: Renleigh Music Corp., c. 1966, 1971. Recorded by Humble Pie on A&M Records.
  - I Don't Want a Doctor, All I Want is a Beautiful Girl
    Words by Ed Rose, music by Jack Mills. New York: Jack Mills, Inc., c. 1919
  - I Don't Want the Morning to Come
    Words by Arthur J. Lamb, music by J. Fred Helf. New York: Helf & Hager Co., Inc., c. 1908. About a young son who may not live.
  - I Don't Want to Get Well
    Words by Harry Pease and Howard Johnson, music by Harry Jentes. New York: Leo Feist, 1917. Image of a young man in a military hospital treated by a young nurse.
  - I Got a "Code" in My "Doze"
    By Arthur Fields, Fred Hall, and Billy Rose, New York: Santly Bros., Inc., c. 1929.
  - I Have Such a Shocking Cold
    Words by D. O'C. Townley, music by P. Rondinella. Philadelphia: Lee & Walker, c. 1869. The singer has such a bad cold that he cannot sing.
  - I Knocked at the Door with a Rat-a-tat-tat, or, The Doctor
    Words and music by Frank Leo. London: Frank Dean & Co., c. 1900. Sung by the doctor.
  - I Need Vitamin U
    Words by Iola Daniel, music by Bob Keith. New York: Barton Music Corp., c. 1944.
  - I Never Believed in Angels Until I Met You
    Words by Robert F. Roden, music by Peter De Rose. New York: F. B. Haviland Pub, Co., Inc., c. 1918. On a Red Cross nurse in World War I.
  - I Take Pink Pills for Pale People
    Words and music by Jack Foley. London: Herman Darewski Music Publishing Co., c. 1919
  - I Want a New Drug
    Words and music by Chris Hayes and Huey Lewis. N.p.: Hulex Music, c. 1984. "As recorded by Huey Lewis and the News on Chrysalis Records.
  - I Want a Nurse
    Words by George Weiss, music by Ken Macomber. New York: Wise Music Publications, c. 1946.
  - I Will Repay: In Memory of Edith Cavell
    Words and music by F. V. St. Clair. London: E. Marks & Son, c. 1915. On the death of nurse Edith Cavell.
  - I Woke Up with a Cold
    By Irving Caesar, simplified piano arrangements by Sidney Green. New York: Irving Caesar, c. 1948. A health song for children, one of several by Caesar.
  - If You Catch a Little Cold (I'll Sneeze For You)
    Words by Buddy Kaye, music by Hal Borne. New York: Bregman, Vocco & Conn, Inc., c. 1951. "Recorded by Dinah Shore and Tony Martin on RCA Records."
  - I'll Make You Up A Bottle
    Words and music by Lester Barrett. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). Sung by the "doctor."
  - I'm a Nurse for Aching Hearts
    Words by Gene Buck, music by Louis A. Hirsch. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1915. "Ziegfield Follies 1915." Sung by the "nurse."
  - I'm All Broke Out With Blues
    Words and music by Jimmy Conzelman. Milwaukee, Wisconsin: Lipman, Schultz and Sherman, c. 1923. Image of a patient with spots on his face in bed.
  - I'm Cert'nly Feelin' Bad
    By Hamilton and Fischer. New York: Jos. W. Stern & Co., c. 1904. "The Popular Western 'Rag-time Shout' introduced by the inimitable Stella Mayhew."
  - I'm Getting Better and Better
    Words and music by Austin Rudd. London: B. Feldman & Co., c. 1922. Sung by Austin Rudd.
  - I'm Getting Better Ev'ry Day
    Words by Percy Edgar, music by Mark Strong. London: Cecil Lennox & Co., c. 1922.
  - I'm on the Water Wagon Now
    Words by Paul West, music by John W. Bratton. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1903. Sung by Frank Daniels in C. B. Dillingham's production of "The Office Boy."
  - I'm Only a Poor Crippled Kiddie
    Words and music by George Nagel. New Brunswick, N.J.: George Nagel, c. 1924. Dedicated to B.P.O. ELKS, Morristown, N.J. No. 815.
  - I'm the Medicine Man for the Blues
    Words by Grant Clark, music by Harry Akst. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1929. From "Is Everybody Happy," a "Warner Bros. Vitaphone Singing Picture" with Ted Lewis and Alice Day.
  - Indian Medicine Man
    By Ada Richter. Philadelphia: Theodore Presser Co., c. 1934. Sung by the "medicine man."
  - Influenza Blues
    Words by Robert B. Smith, music by Malvin M. Franklin and Robert Hood Bowers. New York and Detroit: Jerome H. Remick Co., c. 1919. From "A Lonely Romeo," book by Harry B. Smith and Lew Fields.
  - "Is That Mother Bending O'er Me?" or, The Dying Soldier Boy
    By Wm. Thomas, arranged "by a talented lady of New York." Philadelphia: Wm. Thomas, Publisher, c. 1891. Image of a young man in a Red Cross hospital ward.
  - Is There a Doctor About?
    Words by Norton David, music by Shirley Ilton. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, c. 1907 (in USA)
  - Insanity: A Daffy Ditty
    Words by Jack Norwich, music by Albert Von Tilzer. New York: The York Music Co., c. 1907.
  - Ipecacuanha, or The Doctor's Daugher
    Cover page only. Words by W. W. Thornton, music by Arthur Lloyd. London: H. D'Alcorn & Co., n.d. (19th cent.).
  - It May Be Influenza (But I Think It's Love)
    Words and music by Ernest Longstaffe. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1927. Sung by Tommy Handley.
  - It's All Up to You (To Make North Carolina No. 1 in Good Health)
    Words by Sammy Cahn, music by Jule Styne. New York; Edwin H. Morris & Co., c. 1946. "The song written for and donated to the Good Health Association by Sammy Cahn [and] Jule Styne." The Good Health Plan calls for legislation to expand the number of doctors, nurses, hospitals, and health centers in the state.
  - I've Got a Pain in My Sawdust
    Words by Henry E. Warner, music by Herman Avery Wade. New York: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, c. 1935. Originally copyright by Jos. A. Stern & Co., 1908. "The plaint of the little bisque doll."
  - I've Got a Sweet Tooth Bothering Me (Pull it Out, Pull it Out, Pull it Out)
    Words and music by Irving Berlin. New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Co., c. 1916. Sung by Clark and Bergman. Refers to the dentist.
  - I've Got the Mumps
    Words and music by Irene Franklin and Burt Green. New York: Leo Feist, c. 1909. Copyright 1909 by Irene Franklin and Burt Green. Copyright 1909 by Leo Feist. Sung by a child who has the mumps.
  - I've Got the Mumps
    Words and music by Irene Franklin and Burt Green. New York: Leo Feist, c. 1909. Sung by a child who has the mumps. Later version of the previous item.
  - I've Got the Ooperzootic
    Words by Harry Hunter, music by Edmund Forman. London: Francis, Day & Hunter, n.d. (ca. 1899). "Sung by Johnny Danvers of the Mohawk Minstrels, Royal Agricultural Hall, London." "My wife's a Lady Doctor,..."
  - I've Got the Reumatiz
    Word and Music by Carl Summers. Columbus, Ohio: The Buckeye Music Pub. Co., c. 1918.
  - I've Had the Measles
    By Eddie Pola, Robert Nesbitt, and William Walker. London: Chappell & Co., c. 1934. From "Here's How."
  - I've Still Got My Health
    Words and music by Cole Porter. London, New York: Chappell & Co., c. 1940. From "Panama Hattie."
  - Jefferson Medical College March and Two-Step
    Composed by Samuel Stephens. Norristown, Pa.: Samuel Stephens & Co., c. 1900. "As played by the Jefferson Orchestra."
  - Jeremiah Peabody's Poly Unsaturated Quick Dissolving Fast Acting Pleasant Tasting Green and Purple Pills
    By Ray Stevens. North Atlanta, Ga.: Lowery Music Co., Inc., c. 1961. Recorded by Ray Stevens on Mercury Records.
  - Ju-Jah
    Words and music by E. W. Rogers. London: Hopwood & Crew, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). Sung by James Fawn. Comic song about a cure-all.
  - Kane's Funeral March
    Composed by William H. Shuster. Philadelphia: William H. Shuster, n.d. (ca. 1857). "Composed and respectfully inscribed to the memory of Elisha Kent Kane, M.D., U.S.N."
  - The Keeley Cure
    Words and music by James Thornton. New York: Frank Harding's Music House, c. 1902. "Irish Comic Song."
  - Keep Smiling
    Words and music by A. W. Schwietert, D.C. Marshalltown, Iowa: A. W. Schwietert, D.C., 1917. About chiropractic.
  - The Keys of Love, and Calomel Song
    Broadside with the words two separate songs. "The Keys of Love" has no medical content. The words of "Calomel Song" are similar to those of "Go Call the Doctor & Be Quick! Or Anti Calomel." "Sold, wholesale and retail, by L. Deming, No. 62, Hanover Street 2nd door from Friend Street, Boston. No date, but likely early to mid 19th century.
  - K-I-S-S Kiss
    Words by Blanche Merrill, music by Leo Edwards. New York: Chas. K. Harris, c. 1912. Duet on correcting lisping. From "The Trained Nurses" with Clark & Bergman, and produced by Jesse L. Lasky.
  - Die kranke Puppe. Dolly's Doctor
    By Erik Meyer-Helmund, English words by Paul England. Leipzig: Bosworth & Co., c. 1896. German and English text.
  - Lady in White (Box 4)
    Words and music by Sylvia Rossi. Hollywood, California: Cine-Mart Music Publishers, c. 1944. On nurses in World War II.
  - Laughing Gas or A Night at the Polytechnic
    Cover page only. Words and music by John Nash. London: Simpson & Co., n.d. (late 19th cent.). Sung by John Nash.
  - Let Me Kiss Him For His Mother!
    Words and music by John P. Ordway. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co., 1859. Illustration of a sickroom scene.
  - Let's All Do Something (Uncle Sammy Wants Us Now)
    Words by Andrew B. Sterling, music by Arthur Lange. New York: Joe Morris Music Co., c. 1917. On serving the nation including Red Cross nursing. Nurse on cover does not have a red cross on her uniform.
  - Let's All Do Something (Uncle Sammy Wants Us Now)
    Words by Andrew B. Sterling, music by Arthur Lange. New York: Joe Morris Music Co., c. 1917. On serving the nation including Red Cross nursing. Nurse on cover has red crosses on her uniform.
  - Let's All Join the Red Cross Band
    Words by H. W. Rotavele an Henry J. Secord, music by Michael Jackson. Duluth, Minn.: Jackson Music Pub. Co., c. 1917. Sung by Doris Roche.
  - Let's Help the Red Cross Now
    By Ted S. Barron. New York: Metropolis Music Co., c. 1917. "Sincerely dedicated to the American Red Cross."
  - The Little Good For Nothing's Good For Something After All
    Words by Lou Klein, music by Harry Von Tilzer. New York: Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co., c. 1918. On a girl called a tomboy and "good-for-nothing" who became a Red Cross nurse.
  - Little Teddy
    By Ben Chadwick. Springfield, Mass.: Phelps Music Co., c. 1897. Image of Luke Fildes, "The Doctor'" on the cover. The blacksmith's child is cured by prayer.
  - Love is a Seidlitz Powder: Humorous Song
    Words and music by Walter Dowling. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1908. Sung by Walter Dowling.
  - Love is a Sickness
    Words by Samuel Daniel (1562-1619), music by T. Wilkinson Stephenson. New York: Boosey & Co., c. 1926.
  - Maggie's Cold: Comedy Fox-Trot
    Words and music by Harry Tilsley, Robert Hargreaves, and Stanley J. Damerell. London: Cecil Lennox, Ltd, c. 1929. Sung by Tommy Handley.
  - Maladies and Medicines: A Song of Hospital-ity.
    Words an music by M. Dee. London: C. Sheard, n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). Sung by the Christys Minstrels. Comic song noting a large number of ailments and remedies.
  - Mama, My Nurse Spanked Me
    Words and music by Norris Span'Kasse. Lake Charles, Louisiana: Who Manuscripts, c., 1949. The "nurse" here is a caretaker.
  - Medic Rag
    Composed by C. L. Woolsey. Detroit and New York: Jerome H. Remick & Co., c.1910. Image of two medical graduates smoking in front of a large skull.
  - The Medic Theme
    By Victor Young. Beverly Hills, California: Victor Young Publications, Inc., c. 1955. From the NBC television show, "Medic." Recorded by Victor Young on Decca Records and by Les Banter on Capitol Records.
  - The Medical Student
    Words Albert Smith, music by J. Valentine. London: Leoni Lee, Metropolitan Music Repository, n.d. (mid 19th cent.).
  - Medicine Jack
    Words and music by Alfred Scott Gatty. London: Robert Cocks & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). On a quack selling remedies.
  - The Medicine Man
    By Bert Williams and George Walker, arranged by W. H. Tyers. New York: Jos. W. Stern & Co., c. 1899. "Coon Song." "Williams and Walker's Latest Laughing Wrinkle!" Williams and Walker, pictured on the cover, were African-Americans.
  - The Medicine Man
    By Bert Williams and George Walker, Arranged by W. H. Tyer. Copyright 1899 by Jos. W. Stern & Co. Assigned to Edward B. Marks Music Co., New York. "A Coon Song." Sold as part of a series "Well-Known Bert Williams Series of Song Hits." Williams and Walker were African-Americans.
  - Medicine Man
    Words and music by Terry Cashman, Gene Pistilli, and T. P. West. New York: Sandbox Music, Inc. and Blendingwell Music, Inc., c. 1969. "Recorded by Buchanan Brothers on Event 3302."
  - The Medicine Song
    Words and music by "Hawk" Wolinksi. London: Overdue Music/ W B Music Corp., Warner Bros. Music Ltd., c. 1948. "Recorded by Stephanie Mills on Club/Phonogram."
  - Microbes
    Words and music by E. Shirk Cole. New York: The S. Brainard's Sons Co., c. 1905
  - Mike's Took Bad
    Words by Merrick Fifield McCarthy, music by Victor Young. Philadelphia: Theodore Presser Co., c. 1945.
  - The Mock Doctor: Quadrille on Melodies from Gounod's Opera
    Title page only. No music. By Camille Schubert. London: Chappell & Co., n.d. (19th cent.).
  - Morison's Pills
    By "Pilula Rhubarbus M.D." London: Leoni Lee, n.d. (ca. 1830s). Sung by Mr. Fitzwilliam. A satire on Morison's Pills and James Morison's "College of Health".
  - The Morning After the Night Before
    Words by Ed. Moran, music by J. Fred Helf. New York: J. Fred Helf, c. 1910. "Lew Dockstader's New Comic Song." On hangovers. Mention of "women's rights."
  - Mister Chiropractor
    Words and music by Philip Francis Phelp. Copyright 1928 by Philip Francis Phelp. Published by Popular Songs Publishing Company, Los Angeles, in Magazine of Popular Songs 5(9) (September 1928): 2-4, along with four other songs.
  - Mr. Captain Stop the Ship!
    Words by W. A. Archbold, music by Felix McGlennon. New York: Spaulding & Gray, c. 1894. On motion sickness.
  - Mrs. Winslow's Soothing Syrup (A Cradle Song)
    Music by Karl P. Harrington. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, c. 1893. Although this song advertises a patent medicine to soothe cranky babies, it is here marketed as a "Humorous Quartet for Male Voices" in a list of other "Part-Songs for Men's Voices."
  - Mumpy Mumps: Cute Child Impersonation
    Words by Lucile Crites, music by Alma Stanley. Belmar, N.J.: Edgar S. Werner & Co., c. 1929. Copyright 1929 by M. S. Titus Werner.
  - Mumps!
    Words by Florence B. Steiner, music by Bertha Louise Tamblyn. Copyright by Florence B. Steiner and Bertha Tamblyn in Canada and the USA, 1932. Printed by the Draper Music Co., Toronto.
  - Musical Influenza
    By Gwen Lewis. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1957. "Concerted medley for comedian and four others."
  - Musical Maladies
    Words by Medley Barrett and Byam Wyke, music by Medley Barrett. London: Reynolds & Co., n.d. (early 20th cent.). Uses musical terms to represent maladies.
  - My Angel of the Flaming Cross
    Words and music by Byron Gay. New York: Sunset Publishing Co., c. 1918. On a Red Cross nurse in World War I.
  - My Dream of the Big Parade
    Words by Al Dubin, music by Jimmy McHugh. New York: Jack Mills, Inc., c. 1926. Memories of World War I.
  - My Influenza
    Words by Robert Rutherford, music by Harold Arpthorp. London: Reynolds & Co., c. 1918. Sung by W. Scott-Gordon.
  - My Nurse Corps Nightingale
    Words and music by John J. Torbik and George E. Banbury. New York: George F. Briegel, Inc., c. 1945. Images of specific World War II nurses on cover.
  - My Red Cross Girlie: The Wound is Somewhere in My Heart
    Words by Harry Bewley, music by Theodore Morse. New York: Leo. Feist, c. 1917. On Red Cross nurses in World War I.
  - My Two Front Teeth (All I Want for Christmas is)
    Words and music by Don Gardner. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c. 1943.
  - Nerves
    Words by Carolus Rex, music by Jan Van Dee. London: B. Feldman & Co.. c. 1922. Nerves as a cause of every ailment.
  - Nerves!
    Words by P. G. Wodehouse, music by Jean Schwartz. New York: T. B. Harms Co., c. 1919. By arrangement with Jerome H. Remick & Co., New York. From the musical comedy "See You Later."
  - The Nerves: Comic Song
    Cover only. No music. "Written and sung by French & Harvey." London: B. Williams II, n.d. (mid 19th cent.).
  - Neurotic You and Psychopathic Me
    Words and music by Charles Gaynor. New York: Southern Music Publishing Co. Copyright 1949 by Charles Gaynor, New York. From the musical production "Lend Me an Ear."
  - Never See His Mother Any More
    Words by Bennett Scott, music by A. J. Mills. London: Frank Dean & Co., c. 1896. Humorous song, with a verse about a medical quack.
  - No Matter What Flag He Fought Under (He Was Some Mother's Boy After All)
    Words by J. Will Callahan, music by F. Henri Klickmann. Chicago: Frank K. Root & Co., c. 1915. On World War I soldiers and Red Cross nurses.
  - A Nurse's Pledge
    Words by Etta Frances Wooders, music by Augustus Carbone. Mineola, N.Y.: C. N. Carbone, Dow and Dow, Music Publishers. Copyright 1939 by M. A. Wooders and C. N. Carbone.
  - Nursie
    Words by Arthur Chapman, music by Theo. Bonheur. London: Osborn & Co., n.d. (turn of 20th cent.). The "nurse" is the caretaker of a child rather than a trained nurse.
  - Nursie! Nursie!
    Words and music by Art Noel and Don Pelosi. London: Bradbury Wood Ltd., c. 1939. A nurse catches the eye of soldiers walking in the park. "Featured by Randolph Sutton."
  - Nursie! Nursie!
    Words and music by Art Noel and Don Pelosi. London: Bradbury Wood Ltd., c. 1939. See previous entry. "Featured by Jim Davidson and His A.B.C. Orchestra."
  - Nursie! Nursie!
    Words and music by Art Noel and Don Pelosi. London: Bradbury Wood Ltd., c. 1939. See first entry under this title. "Featured by 'The Little Big Four.'"
  - Nursie! Nursie!
    Words and music by Art Noel and Don Pelosi. New ed. New York: T. B. Harms, Co., c. 1942. Recorded by Connee Boswell.
  - Nursie! Nursie!
    Words and music by Art Noel and Don Pelosi. New ed. New York: T. B. Harms Co., c. 1942. "Featured by Gracie Fields."
  - Ocean Honeymoon (Box 5)